Register of the Pathfinder Press Publications, 1922-2014
Hoover Institution Archives
- MERIT PUBLISHERS IMPRINTS, 1965-1969. (Box 4-6)
  - Munis, Grandizo. What Policy for Revolutionists: Marxism or Ultra-Leftism? By Grandizo Munis and James P. Cannon. 64 p. Reprint of Pioneer Publishers edition, 1969.
  - Novack, George. How Can the Jews Survive? A Socialist Answer to Zionism. 22 p. Cf. Pathfinder (1970) imprint, 1969.
  - Novack, George. Revolutionary Dynamics of Women's Liberation. 22 p. Cf. Pathfinder (1973) imprint, 1969.
  - Reed, Evelyn. Problems of Women's Liberation: A Marxist Approach. 63 p. Cf. Pathfinder (1970), Related U.S. (1972) and Related Foreign (Argentina, Brazil, India, Italy, Japan, Mexico, Netherlands, Spain) imprints, 1969.
  - Revolutionary Analysis, Strategy and Tactics Today. 31 p., 1969.
  - Revueltas, Jose. The Youth Movement and the Alienation of Society. 34 p. Cf. Pathfinder (1971) imprint, 1969.
  - Ring, Harry. How Cuba Uprooted Race Discrimination. 2nd edition. 15 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers (1961, q.v.) Cf. Pathfinder (1972) imprint, 1969.
  - Shriver, George. Rebels and Bureaucrats: Soviet Conflicts as Seen in Solzhenitsyn's Cancer Ward. By George Saunders [pseudonym] 59 p., 1969.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Chinese Revolution: Problems and Perspectives. 2nd edition. 23 p., 1969.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Fascism: What It Is, How to Fight It. 31 p. Reprint of Pioneer Publishers edition (1944, q.v.) Cf. Pathfinder (1970) imprint, 1969.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Trotsky on Engels and Kautsky. 30 p., 1969.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Trotsky on the Labor Party in the United States. 35 p., 1969.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Trotsky on the Trade Unions. 80 p. Cf. Pathfinder (1972) imprint, 1969.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Permanent Revolution. Bound with Leon Trotsky, Results and Prospects. 281 p. Cf. Pioneer (1931), Pathfinder (1986) and Related Foreign (Spain) imprints, 1969.
  - Vernon, Robert. The Black Ghetto. Expanded edition. 31 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Italy) imprint, 1969.
- PATHFINDER PRESS IMPRINTS, 1969-1993. (Box 6-23)
  Books and pamphlets published by Pathfinder Press. All items published in New York City unless otherwise specified. Arranged chronologically.
  - Breitman, George. The Assassination of Malcolm X. By George Breitman and Herman Porter. 31 p. Cf. 1976 imprint, 1969. (Box 6)
  - Camejo, Peter. How to Make a Revolution in the U.S. 23 p., 1969.
  - ----------. 6th printing. 23 p., 1975.
  - Frank, Pierre. Key Problems of the Transition from Capitalism to Socialism. By Pierre Frank, George Novack and Ernest Mandel. 63 p., 1969.
  - ----------. 3rd printing. 63 p., 1973.
  - X, Malcolm. Malcolm X Talks to Young People. 2nd edition. 29 p., 1969.
  - ----------. 5th printing. 29 p., 1979.
  - ----------. 8th printing. 29 p., 1988.
  - ----------. 9th printing. 29 p. Cf. 1991 imprint, 1989.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Writings of Leon Trotsky, 1929-1940. 1969-1979. Volumes: 1929, 1930, 1930-31, 1932, 1932-33, 1933-34, 1935-36, 1937-38, 1938-39, 1939-40, Supplement: 1929-33, Supplement: 1934-40. Two volumes, 1938-39 and 1939-40, published under Merit Publishers imprint (Box 6-7)
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 1974-1978. Volumes: 1933-34, 1934-35, 1935-36, 1936-37, 1937-38, 1938-39, 1939-40 (Box 7-8)
  - Bravo, Douglas. Douglas Bravo Speaks: Interview with Venezuelan Guerrilla Leader. 23 p., 1970. (Box 8)
  - Cagle, Tom. Life in an Auto Plant. 23 p., 1970.
  - Camejo, Peter. Liberalism, Ultraleftism or Mass Action. 15 p., 1970.
  - Castro, Fidel. Women and the Cuban Revolution. By Fidel Castro and Linda Jenness. 15 p. Cf. 1981 imprint, 1970.
  - Compean, Mario. La Raza Unida Party in Texas. By Mario Compean and Jose Angel Gutierrez. 15 p., 1970.
  - Debs, Eugene V. Eugene V. Debs Speaks. Edited by Jean Y. Tussey. 320 p., 1970.
  - DuBois, W. E. B. W. E. B. DuBois Speaks: Speeches and Addresses. Edited by Dr. Philip S. Foner. 2 volumes, 1970.
  - Edwards, Theodore. Marxism and Christianity: Are They Compatible? A Debate. By Theodore Edwards and Rev. Blase Bonpane. 21 p., 1970.
  - GIs Speak Out against the War: The Case of the Fort Jackson Eight: Interviews of Participants. By Fred Halstead. 128 p., 1970.
  - Hansen, Joseph. The "Population Explosion": How Socialists View It. 2nd edition of Too Many Babies? 47 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers (1960, q.v.), 1970.
  - ----------. Too Many Babies? The Myth of the Population Explosion. 3rd edition. 43 p., 1987.
  - Knight, Etheridge. Black Voices from Prison. By Etheridge Knight and other inmates of Indiana State Prison. 189 p., 1970. (Box 9)
  - Kofsky, Frank. Black Nationalism and the Revolution in Music. 280 p., 1970.
  - Leon, Abram. The Jewish Question: A Marxist Interpretation. 2nd edition. 270 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Italy, Japan) imprints, 1970.
  - Lund, Caroline. Women and the Equal Rights Amendment. By Caroline Lund and Betsey Stone. 15 p., 1970.
  - Luxemburg, Rosa. Reform or Revolution. 53 p., 1970.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 79 p., 1973.
  - Luxemburg, Rosa. Rosa Luxemburg Speaks. Edited by Mary-Alice Waters. 473 p., 1970.
  - Mandel, Ernest. The Marxist Theory of Alienation. By Ernest Mandel and George Novack. 63 p., 1970.
  - ----------. 5th printing. 94 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Turkey) imprint, 1986.
  - Mandel, Ernest. Peaceful Coexistence and World Revolution. 31 p., 1970.
  - Mandel, Ernest. Revolutionary Strategy in the Imperialist Countries. 15 p., 1970.
  - Marx, Karl. The Communist Manifesto. By Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels. 47 p., 1970.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 47 p., 1987.
  - ----------. 2nd printing. 47 p. Cf. 1992 and Related U.S. (1976) imprints, 1988.
  - Miller, Ruthann. In Defense of the Women's Movement. By Ruthann Miller, Mary-Alice Waters and Evelyn Reed. 15 p., 1970.
  - Novack, George. Genocide against the Indians: Its Role in the Rise of U.S. Capitalism. 31 p., 1970.
  - Novack, George. How Can the Jews Survive? A Socialist Answer to Zionism. 22 p. Reprint of Merit Publishers edition (1969, q.v.), 1970.
  - Novack, George. Marxism versus Neo-Anarchist Terrorism. 15 p., 1970.
  - La Raza! Why a Chicano Party? Why Chicano Studies? By Roger Alvarado et al. 15 p., 1970.
  - ----------. 2nd printing. 15 p., 1970.
  - Reed, Evelyn. Problems of Women's Liberation: A Marxist Approach. 2nd enlarged edition. 96 p. First published by Merit Publishers (1969, q.v.) Cf. Related U.S. (1972) and Related Foreign (Argentina, Brazil, India, Italy, Japan, Mexico, Netherlands, Spain) imprints, 1970.
  - Roberts, Dick. The Fraud of Black Capitalism. 15 p., 1970.
  - Stone, Betsey. Sisterhood Is Powerful. 15 p., 1970.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Death Agony of Capitalism and the Tasks of the Fourth International: The Transitional Program. 4th edition. 46 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers (1946, q.v.) Cf. 1973 and Related Foreign (Argentina, Japan, Spain) imprints, 1970.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Fascism: What It Is, How to Fight It. 31 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers (1944, q.v.), 1970.
  - ----------. 3rd printing. 31 p. Cf. Merit (1969) imprint, 1972.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Trotsky on the Jewish Question. 31 p., 1970.
  - ----------. 3rd printing. 31 p., 1980.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Trotsky on the Paris Commune. 63 p., 1970.
  - ----------. 3rd printing. 63 p., 1987.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Trotsky on the Suppressed Testament of Lenin. 3rd edition. 47 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers (1935, q.v.), 1970.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Marxism in Our Time. 47 p., 1970.
  - Trotsky, Leon. My Life: An Attempt at an Autobiography. 602 p., 1970.
  - ----------. 8th printing. 604 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Great Britain) imprint, 1991.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Problems of Civil War. 23 p., 1970. (Box 10)
  - Trotsky, Leon. Stalinism and Bolshevism: Concerning the Historical and Theoretical Roots of the Fourth International. 29 p. Reprint of Pioneer Publishers edition (1960, q.v.), 1970.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Third International after Lenin. 346 p. Reprint of Pioneer Publishers edition (1936, q.v.), 1970.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Women and the Family. 47 p., 1970.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 78 p., 1973.
  - Waters, Mary-Alice. The Politics of Women's Liberation Today. 23 p., 1970.
  - Williams, Maxine. Black Women's Liberation. By Maxine Williams and Pamela Newman. 15 p., 1970.
  - X, Malcolm. By Any Means Necessary: Speeches, Interviews, and a Letter. 184 p., 1970.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 191 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Italy) imprint, 1992.
  - X, Malcolm. Malcolm X on Afro-American History. Expanded and illustrated edition. 74 p. First published by Merit Publishers (1967, q.v.), 1970.
  - ----------. 9th printing. 74 p., 1988.
  - ----------. 3rd edition. 93 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Netherlands) imprint, 1990.
  - Braverman, Harry. Sam Adams and the American Revolution. By Harry Frankel [pseudonym] 47 p., 1971.
  - Breitman, George. Black Nationalism and Socialism. By George Breitman and George Novack. 31 p. Reprint of Merit Publishers edition, 1971.
  - Breitman, George. How a Minority Can Change Society: The Real Potential of the Afro-American Struggle. 2nd edition. 30 p. Cf. Related U.S. (1964) and Merit (1966) imprints, 1971.
  - Breitman, George. The New Radicalization Compared with Those of the Past. 30 p., 1971.
  - Breitman, George. Race Prejudice: How It Began, When It Will End. 1971. Revised edition of Anti-Negro Prejudice. 15 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers q.v.), (1960
  - Camejo, Peter. Allende's Chile: Is It Going Socialist? 31 p., 1971.
  - Cannon, James P. Speeches for Socialism. 462 p., 1971.
  - The Case for an Independent Black Party. 2nd edition. 23 p. Cf. Related U.S. (1968) imprint, 1971.
  - Cleage, Albert. Myths about Malcolm X: Two Views. By Rev. Albert Cleage and George Breitman. 30 p. Reprint of Merit Publishers edition, 1971.
  - Documents of the Chicano Struggle. 15 p., 1971.
  - Documents of the Palestinian Resistance Movement. 23 p., 1971.
  - Evans, Les. The Wage Price Freeze Swindle. By Les Evans and Linda Jenness. 23 p., 1971.
  - Fifty Years of World Revolution: An International Symposium. Edited by Ernest Mandel. 366 p. Reprint of Merit Publishers edition, 1971.
  - Foley, Gerry. Ireland in Rebellion. 31 p., 1971.
  - Jenness, Doug. Lenin as Election Campaign Manager. 15 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Mexico) imprint, 1971.
  - Jenness, Linda. Abortion: A Woman's Right. By Linda Jenness, Caroline Lund and Cindy Jaquith. 14 p., 1971.
  - Kate Millett's Sexual Politics: A Marxist Appreciation. By Kipp Dawson et al. 31 p., 1971.
  - Lund, Caroline. The Family: Revolutionary or Oppressive Force? 22 p., 1971.
  - ----------. The Family: Progressive or Oppressive? 2nd printing. 22 p., 1973.
  - Mandel, Ernest. The Marxist Theory of the State. 31 p. Reprint of Merit Publishers edition (1969, q.v.), 1971.
  - Mandel, Ernest. The Revolutionary Student Movement: Theory and Practice. 2nd edition. 46 p. Cf. Related U.S. (1969) imprint, 1971.
  - May 1970: Birth of the Antiwar University. 62 p., 1971.
  - Novack, George. Democracy and Revolution. 286 p. Cf. Related Foreign (India, Spain) imprints, 1971.
  - Novack, George. Empiricism and Its Evolution: A Marxist View. 164 p. Reprint of Merit Publishers edition, 1971.
  - Novack, George. An Introduction to the Logic of Marxism. 5th edition. 144 p. Cf. Related U.S. (1942), Pioneer (1963), Merit (1966) and Related Foreign (Argentina, Greece, Mexico, Spain) imprints, 1971.
  - Novack, George. The Origins of Materialism. 300 p. Reprint of Merit Publishers edition, 1971. (Box 11)
  - Reed, Evelyn. An Answer to The Naked Ape and Other Books on Aggression. 23 p., 1971.
  - Reosti, Ronald. The Pollution Crisis: Who Is Responsible? 14 p., 1971.
  - Revueltas, Jose. The Youth Movement and the Alienation of Society. 34 p. Reprint of Merit Publishers edition (1969, q.v.), 1971.
  - Rius. Cuba for Beginners: An Illustrated Guide for Americans (and Their Government) to Socialist Cuba. 2nd edition. 153 p., 1971.
  - Roberts, Dick. Mideast Oil and U.S. Imperialism. 23 p., 1971.
  - Thomas, Tony. Black Power in the Caribbean: The 1970 Upsurge in Trinidad. By Tony Thomas and John Riddell. 15 p., 1971.
  - Thomas, Tony. In Defense of Black Nationalism: An Answer to the Communist Party and Young Workers Liberation League. 30 p., 1971.
  - Towards an American Socialist Revolution: A Strategy for the 1970s. By Jack Barnes et al. 207 p., 1971.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Europe and America: Two Speeches on Imperialism. 63 p., 1971.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Military Writings. 160 p. Reprint of Merit Publishers edition, 1971.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Struggle against Fascism in Germany. 479 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Great Britain) imprint, 1971.
  - Vidal, Mirta. Chicanas Speak Out: Women, New Voice of La Raza. 15 p., 1971.
  - Vidal, Mirta. Chicano Liberation and Revolutionary Youth. 15 p., 1971.
  - Woodroofe, Debby. Sisters in Struggle, 1848-1920. 31 p., 1971.
  - Young, Arthur. Quebec Nationalism: Its Roots and Meaning. 23 p., 1971.
  - Blanco, Hugo. Hugo Blanco on Chile and Peru. 15 p., 1972.
  - Blanco, Hugo. Land or Death: The Peasant Struggle in Peru. 178 p. Cf. Related U.S. (1967) and Related Foreign (Japan, Sweden) imprints, 1972.
  - Browne, Robert S. On Black Separatism. By Robert S. Browne and Robert Vernon. Reprint of Should the U.S. Be Partitioned into Two Separate and Independent Nations? 30 p. First published by Merit Publishers (1968, q.v.), 1972.
  - Camejo, Peter. Crisis and Repression in Argentina. By Peter Camejo and Nahuel Moreno. 23 p., 1972.
  - Camejo, Peter. Guevara's Guerrilla Strategy: A Critique and Some Proposals. 30 p. Cf. 1974 imprint, 1972.
  - Cannon, James P. The History of American Trotskyism: From Its Origins (1928) to the Founding of the Socialist Workers Party (1938): Report of a Participant. 2nd edition. 268 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers, 1972.
  - Cannon, James P. The Struggle for a Proletarian Party. Edited by John G. Wright. 2nd edition. 302 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers. Cf. Education for Socialists (1979) and Related Foreign (France, Germany) imprints, 1972.
  - Chainey, Steve. The High School Revolt. 23 p., 1972.
  - Corona, Bert. Bert Corona Speaks on La Raza Unida Party and the "Illegal Alien" Scare. 23 p., 1972.
  - Corona, Bert. Bert Corona habla del Partido de la Raza Unida y del alarma en contra de los "ilegales" [Bert Corona Speaks... Spanish version] 23 p., 1972.
  - Cruse, Harold. Marxism and the Negro Struggle. By Harold Cruse, George Breitman and Clifton DeBerry. 46 p. Reprint of Pioneer Publishers edition (1965, q.v.), 1972.
  - Engels, Friedrich. The Origin of the Family, Private Property, and the State. 191 p., 1972.
  - Engels, Friedrich. Socialism: Utopian and Scientific. 63 p., 1972.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 63 p., 1989.
  - Feminism and Socialism. Edited by Linda Jenness. 160 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Spain) imprint, 1972.
  - Foley, Gerry. Problems of the Irish Revolution: Can the IRA Meet the Challenge? 31 p., 1972.
  - Hansen, Joseph. Nixon's Moscow and Peking Summits: Their Meaning for Vietnam. By Joseph Hansen and Caroline Lund. 31 p., 1972.
  - Jenness, Linda. Socialism and Democracy. 23 p., 1972.
  - Johnson, Joe. The Prison Revolt. 22 p., 1972.
  - Morrison, Derrick. Attica: Why Prisoners Are Rebelling. By Derrick Morrison and Mary-Alice Waters. 15 p., 1972.
  - Morrison, Derrick. Black Liberation and Political Power: The Meaning of the Gary Convention. By Derrick Morrison and Tony Thomas. 23 p., 1972.
  - Preis, Art. Labor's Giant Step: Twenty Years of the CIO. 2nd edition. 538 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers, 1972. (Box 12)
  - Reed, Evelyn. Is Biology Woman's Destiny? 23 p., 1972.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 31 p. Cf. Related U.S. (ca. 1970s) and Related Foreign (Nepal) imprints, 1985.
  - Revolutionary Marxist Students in Poland Speak Out, 1964-1968. By Jacek Kuron et al. 2nd edition. 96 p. First published by Merit Publishers, 1972.
  - Ring, Harry. Cuba and Problems of Workers' Democracy. 15 p., 1972.
  - Ring, Harry. How Cuba Uprooted Race Discrimination. 15 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers (1961, q.v.) Cf. Merit (1969) imprint, 1972.
  - Roberts, Dick. China and the USA: Behind the Great Turnabout. 30 p., 1972.
  - Socialist Workers Party. A Revolutionary Strategy for the 70s: Documents of the Socialist Workers Party. 96 p., 1972.
  - Socialist Workers Party. The Struggle for Chicano Liberation. 30 p., 1972.
  - A Strategy for Revolutionary Youth. 2nd edition. 29 p., 1972.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Trotsky on Black Nationalism and Self-Determination. 63 p. Reprint of Merit Publishers edition (1967, q.v.), 1972.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 95 p., 1978.
  - ----------. 4th printing. 95 p., 1992.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Trotsky on Literature and Art. Edited by Paul N. Siegel. 2nd edition. 252 p., 1972.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Trotsky on the Trade Unions. 79 p. Reprint of Merit Publishers edition (1969, q.v.), 1972.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 80 p., 1975.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Trotsky Speaks. 333 p., 1972.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Revolution Betrayed: What Is the Soviet Union and Where Is It Going? 5th edition. 314 p. Cf. 1992, Pioneer (1945) and Related Foreign (Spain) imprints, 1972.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Stalin School of Falsification. 3rd edition. 338 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers (1937, q.v.), 1972.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Their Morals and Ours: Marxist versus Liberal Views on Morality: Four Essays. By Leon Trotsky, John Dewey and George Novack. 80 p. Reprint of Merit Publishers edition (1966, q.v.), 1972.
  - ----------. 5th edition. 112 p. Cf. Pioneer (1942) and Related Foreign (Spain) imprints, 1973.
  - Waters, Mary-Alice. Feminism and the Marxist Movement. 43 p., 1972.
  - ----------. 4th printing. 43 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Spain) imprint, 1989.
  - Abortion: Women's Fight for the Right to Choose. By Linda Jenness et al. 14 p., 1973.
  - ----------. By Nancy Brown et al. 2nd edition. 21 p., 1975.
  - Blanco, Hugo. The Coup in Chile: Firsthand Report and Assessment. By Hugo Blanco and other revolutionaries who escaped. 23 p., 1973.
  - Cannon, James P. The First Ten Years of American Communism: Report of a Participant. 343 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Italy) imprint, 1973.
  - Cannon, James P. Letters from Prison. 2nd edition. 362 p. First published by Merit Publishers, 1973. (Box 13)
  - Cannon, James P. Notebook of an Agitator. 2nd edition. 369 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers, 1973.
  - Cannon, James P. Socialism on Trial. 5th edition. 184 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers (1942, q.v.) Cf. 1981, Merit (1969) and Related Foreign (Iran) imprints, 1973.
  - Cannon, James P. Speeches to the Party: The Revolutionary Perspective and the Revolutionary Party. 431 p., 1973.
  - Coontz, Stephanie. What Socialists Stand For. 30 p., 1973.
  - ----------. 2nd printing. 30 p., 1974.
  - Feeley, Dianne. Why Women Need the Equal Rights Amendment. 15 p., 1973.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 22 p., 1976.
  - Fourth International. Documents of the Fourth International: The Formative Years, 1933-40. 448 p., 1973.
  - Frankel, Dave. War in the Middle East: The Socialist View. By Dave Frankel, Dick Roberts and Tony Thomas. 31 p., 1973.
  - Fuentes, Luis. The Fight against Racism in Our Schools: Puerto Rican, Black, and Chinese Community Control in New York City. 15 p. Cf. 1974 imprint, 1973.
  - Guerin, Daniel. Fascism and Big Business. 2nd edition. 318 p., 1973.
  - Horowitz, Gus. The Struggle for Socialist Democracy in the Soviet Bloc. 30 p., 1973.
  - Issues Facing the Labor Movement in the 1970s. Edited by Paul Davidson. 31 p., 1973.
  - Jenness, Linda. Inflation: What Causes It, How to Fight It. By Linda Jenness and Dick Roberts. 22 p., 1973.
  - Lund, Caroline. The Czechoslovak Frame-up Trials and the U.S. Communist Party. 15 p., 1973.
  - Mandel, Ernest. An Introduction to Marxist Economic Theory. 2nd edition. 78 p. Cf. Related U.S. (1968) imprint, 1973.
  - Miah, Malik. The U.S. Role in Southern Africa. 15 p., 1973.
  - Mullen, Robert W. Blacks in America's Wars: The Shift in Attitudes from the Revolutionary War to Vietnam. 96 p., 1973.
  - Myers, Allen. The Watergate Conspiracy: What It Reveals about American Capitalist Society. By Allen Myers, Peter Seidman and Barry Sheppard. 15 p., 1973.
  - Novack, George. Humanism and Socialism. 159 p., 1973.
  - ----------. 3rd printing. 159 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Greece) imprint, 1980.
  - Novack, George. Revolutionary Dynamics of Women's Liberation. 2nd printing. 22 p. First published by Merit Publishers (1969, q.v.), 1973.
  - Perez, Jose G. Viva la Huelga! The Struggle of the Farm Workers. 15 p., 1973.
  - Reed, Evelyn. Abortion and the Catholic Church: Two Feminists Defend Women's Rights. By Evelyn Reed and Claire Moriarty. 14 p., 1973.
  - Rodinson, Maxime. Israel: A Colonial-Settler State? 120 p., 1973.
  - Seidman, Peter. Socialists and the Fight against Anti-Semitism: An Answer to the B'nai B'rith Anti-Defamation League. 31 p., 1973.
  - Serge, Victor. From Lenin to Stalin. 2nd edition. 160 p., 1973.
  - Sheppard, Barry. The Meaning of the Vietnam Accords. By Barry Sheppard and Dick Roberts. 15 p., 1973.
  - Trotsky, Leon. In Defense of Marxism. 2nd edition. 221 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers (1942, q.v.), 1973. (Box 14)
  - ----------. 3rd edition. 221 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Spain) imprint, 1990.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Spanish Revolution, 1931-39. 446 p., 1973.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Transitional Program for Socialist Revolution. 223 p., 1973.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 252 p., 1974.
  - ----------. 3rd edition. 269 p. Cf. 1970, Pioneer (1946) and Related Foreign (Argentina, Japan, Spain) imprints, 1977.
  - Watergate: The View from the Left. 95 p., 1973.
  - Beck, Steve. Energy Crisis: A Bonanza for the Oil Giants. By Steve Beck and Cliff Conner. 31 p., 1974.
  - Black Liberation and Socialism. Edited by Tony Thomas. 207 p., 1974.
  - Camejo, Peter. La guerrilla: Por que fracaso como estrategia: Un analisis marxista revolucionario [Guevara's Guerrilla Strategy. Spanish translation] 46 p. Cf. 1972 imprint, 1974.
  - Chile's Days of Terror: Eyewitness Accounts of the Military Coup. 124 p., 1974.
  - Disaster in Chile: Allende's Strategy and Why It Failed. Edited by Les Evans. 271 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Japan) imprint, 1974.
  - Dynamics of World Revolution Today. 188 p. Cf. 1975 and Related U.S. (1978) imprints, 1974.
  - Evans, Les. Watergate and the Myth of American Democracy. By Les Evans and Allen Myers. 206 p., 1974.
  - Frankel, Dave. Self-Determination in the Mideast: A Debate from the Pages of The Militant and Daily World. By Dave Frankel and Tom Foley. 30 p., 1974.
  - Fuentes, Luis. La lucha contra el racismo en nuestras escuelas [The Fight against Racism in Our Schools. Spanish translation] 15 p. Cf. 1973 imprint, 1974.
  - Glass, C. Frank. Revolutionaries in Mao's Prisons: The Case of the Chinese Trotskyists. By Li Fu-jen [pseudonym] and Peng Shu-tse. 23 p., 1974.
  - Lund, Caroline. The Oil Swindle and Watergate: The Socialist Response to Profiteering and Deception. 14 p., 1974.
  - Lund, Caroline. Portugal in Revolt. By Caroline Lund and Baxter Smith. 14 p., 1974.
  - Mandel, Ernest. The Revolutionary Potential of the Working Class. By Ernest Mandel and George Novack. 2nd edition of On the Revolutionary Potential of the Working Class. 79 p. First published by Merit Publishers (1969, q.v.), 1974.
  - Morrow, Felix. Revolution and Counter-revolution in Spain. Bound with Felix Morrow, The Civil War in Spain. 2nd expanded edition. 262 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers. Cf. Pioneer (1936) and Related Foreign (Greece) imprints, 1974.
  - Myers, Allen. Solzhenitsyn in Exile. 15 p., 1974.
  - Novack, George. The First Three Internationals: Their History and Lessons. By George Novack, Dave Frankel and Fred Feldman. 207 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Colombia) imprint, 1974.